<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on nyando's dev blog</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on nyando's dev blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:22:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Talking to Tiny Things - Part I</title><link>/posts/2021-11-08-talking-to-tiny-things-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:22:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021-11-08-talking-to-tiny-things-1/</guid><description>Last week&amp;rsquo;s post on services failed to materialize, mostly to some design changes I&amp;rsquo;m currently mulling over for factorix, so this week I have something different planned. I wanted to take a break from my regular posts on my factory simulator project to talk about another project I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on. The post will involve a little more low-level programming, but in a &amp;ldquo;high-level&amp;rdquo; language.
Coding a CPU The project I&amp;rsquo;m talking about is a Java processor.</description></item><item><title>Es ist ein (Domain) Model und es sieht gut aus</title><link>/posts/2021-10-26-es-ist-ein-model-und-es-sieht-gut-aus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 09:22:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021-10-26-es-ist-ein-model-und-es-sieht-gut-aus/</guid><description>If you speak German, you probably understood the slightly modified Kraftwerk lyric in the title. If you don&amp;rsquo;t speak German, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have noticed the words &amp;ldquo;domain model&amp;rdquo;. And if you&amp;rsquo;re still reading, it means you ignored the extraneous stuff you didn&amp;rsquo;t understand around those two words and simply clicked because &amp;ldquo;domain model&amp;rdquo; was interesting to you. Congratulations, you&amp;rsquo;re already in the correct mindset for this post.
What is a Domain Model?</description></item><item><title>Factorix - A Factory Simulator</title><link>/posts/2021-10-19-factorix-a-factory-simulator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 09:22:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021-10-19-factorix-a-factory-simulator/</guid><description>This series will chronicle my development process as I work on an academic project. The goal is a simple configurable simulator for factory processes.
The scenario is simple enough: A factory creates a range products by performing a series of jobs on a number of machines in a shop. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Optimizing the sequence of jobs on each machine so that the makespan - the time taken to complete each (or all) products ordered - becomes minimal is a frequently studied problem in computer science.</description></item></channel></rss>